RG 004:128, Simsbury Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Simsbury Probate Court records
1769-1942
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Simsbury District)
35 cubic feet
Record books, 1769-1942; Probate files, 1769-1928.
RG004_128
1913-007 and 2011-004
Historical Note
The Simsbury Probate District was constituted May 1769, from the Hartford Probate District. It also served the following municipalities at various times: Barkhamsted, May 1769 - May 1825; Canton, May 1806 - June 6, 1841; Colebrook, May 1769 - May 1779; Granby, October 1786 - May 1807; Hartland, May 1765 - May 1807; New Hartford, October 1800 - May 1825; and Winchester, May 1769 - May 1779. The Simsbury Probate District merged on January 5, 2011 with the Avon, Canton, and Granby Probate Districts to create the Simsbury Regional Probate District which serves the municipalities of Avon, Canton, Granby, and Simsbury.
Town of Simsbury, Probate District chronology:
May 1670 - May 1769, Hartford District
May 1769 - January 4, 2011, Simsbury District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Simsbury Regional District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, volumes 1-51, 1769-1942. Contact the probate court to access original record books numbered after 51. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1769-1928. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1769-1906 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books in accession 2011-004 are numnbered 1 to 51. There is also an unnumbered volume of bonds.
Probate files in accessions 1913-007 and 2011-004 are arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1913-007 are represented in this index.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2011-004.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Barkhamsted; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Canton; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Colebrook; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Granby; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Hartland; Probate records -- Connecticut -- New Hartford; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Simsbury; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Winchester
Places:
Barkhamsted (Conn.); Canton (Conn.); Colebrook (Conn.); Granby (Conn.); Hartland (Conn.); New Hartford (Conn.); Simsbury (Conn.); Winchester (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2011-004, Record books, 1769-1942 and probate files, 1907-1928, is stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Probate files dated 1921 or later are RESTRICTED pending review by State Archives staff as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-29, 1769-1917; probate files, 1769-1906 (Accession 1913-007); and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1913-007 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): December 5, 1913 (1769-1906).
The record books and probate files in accession 2011-004 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on July 15, 2010.
Container List
- Record books, 1769-1942; 19 cubic feet (52 volumes); 2011-004
  - Records, 1769-1780 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1779-1795 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1794-1800 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1800-1805 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1805-1808 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1808-1814 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1812-1816 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1816-1821 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1821-1826 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1825-1830 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1828-1839 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1831-1838 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1838-1842 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1839-1846 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1846-1852 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1852-1871 (Volume 16)
  - Records, 1861-1866 (Volume 17)
  - Records, 1864-1873 (Volume 18)
  - Records, 1869-1874 (Volume 19)
  - Records, 1874-1878 (Volume 20)
  - Records, 1877-1885 (Volume 21)
  - Records, 1883-1889 (Volume 22)
  - Records, 1888-1894 (Volume 23)
  - Records, 1892-1896 (Volume 24)
  - Records, 1897-1904 (Volume 25)
  - Records, 1904-1908 (Volume 26)
  - Records, 1908-1912 (Volume 27)
  - Records, 1911-1915 (Volume 28)
  - Records, 1911-1917 (Volume 29)
  - Records, 1916-1921 (Volume 30)
  - Records, 1923-1924 (Volume 31)
  - Records, 1924-1925 (Volume 32)
  - Records, 1927-1929 (Volume 33)
  - Records, 1928 (Volume 34)
  - Records, 1928-1929 (Volume 35)
  - Records, 1929-1930 (Volume 36)
  - Records, 1929-1934 (Volume 37)
  - Records, 1930-1931 (Volume 38)
  - Records, 1932-1933 (Volume 39)
  - Records, 1932 (Volume 40)
  - Records, 1931-1937 (Volume 41)
  - Records, 1931-1941 (Volume 42)
  - Records, 1942 (Volume 43)
  - Records, 1942 (Volume 44)
  - Records, 1933 (Volume 45)
  - Records, 1941 (Volume 46)
  - Records, 1935 (Volume 47)
  - Records, 1936 (Volume 48)
  - Records, 1936-1937 (Volume 49)
  - Records, 1936-1937 (Volume 50)
  - Records, 1938 (Volume 51)
  - Bonds, 1881-1913 (Volume unnumbered)
- Probate files, 1769-1906; 15.5 cubic feet; 1913-007
  - Abbe- Alderman, D. (Drawer 1)
  - Alderman, E. - Ames (Drawer 2)
  - Andrews - Bacon, E. (Drawer 3)
  - Bacon, F. - Barber, J. (Drawer 4)
  - Barber, K. - Bates (Drawer 5)
  - Beech - Booth (Drawer 6)
  - Borden - Brown, N. (Drawer 7)
  - Brown, O. - Carter (Drawer 8)
  - Case, Aaron - Case, Austin (Drawer 9)
  - Case, B. - Case, G. (Drawer 10)
  - Case, H. - Case, Levi (Drawer 11)
  - Case, Linus - Case, Simeon (Drawer 12)
  - Case, Solomon - Clifford (Drawer 13)
  - Coe - Cornish, John (Drawer 14)
  - Cornish, Joseph - Derby (Drawer 15)
  - Dewey - Ely, C. (Drawer 16)
  - Ely, D. - Ensign, D. (Drawer 17)
  - Ensign, E. - Frazier, C. (Drawer 18)
  - Frazier, D. - Gillet (Drawer 19)
  - Gilman - Goodwin, Mary (Drawer 20)
  - Goodwin, Michael - Griswold, D. (Drawer 21)
  - Griswold, E. - Hays, B. (Drawer 22)
  - Hays, C. - Hodgkin (Drawer 23)
  - Holcomb, A. - Holcomb, S. (Drawer 24)
  - Holcomb, T. - Hoskins, V. (Drawer 25)
  - Hoskins, W. - Humphrey, Ellen (Drawer 26)
  - Humphrey, Esther - Humphrey, M. (Drawer 27)
  - Humphrey, N. - Johnson (Drawer 28)
  - Jones - Latimer, E. (Drawer 29)
  - Latimer, D. - MacGlenchie (Drawer 30)
  - MacIntyre - Mason, L. (Drawer 31)
  - Mason, R. - Mills, C. (Drawer 32)
  - Mills, D. - Morgan (Drawer 33)
  - Morse - Munigle (Drawer 34)
  - Munrow - Payson (Drawer 35)
  - Pease - Pettibone, M. (Drawer 36)
  - Phelps, George O. (Drawer 37)
  - Phelps, George O. - Pike (Drawer 38)
  - Pinney - Ransom (Drawer 39)
  - Rathbun - Rutherford (Drawer 40)
  - Sage - Sisson (Drawer 41)
  - Skinner - Stebbins, S. (Drawer 42)
  - Stebbins, T. - Terry, R. (Drawer 43)
  - Terry, S. - Tuller, C. (Drawer 44)
  - Tuller, D. - Warren (Drawer 45)
  - Waters - Wilcox, L. (Drawer 46)
  - Wilcox, M. - Z.; Miscellaneous (Drawer 47)
- Inventory Control Book, 1769-1906; T003073
  Index of probate files in accession 1913-007
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate files, 1907-1928; .5 cubic feet; 2011-004
  - Probate files (Box 1)
    Surnames range from Vizner to Zura.